Benjamin Schweizer

Software Developer

Profile

Adventurous coffee professional and polyglot turned programmer. I am pursuing a career in Software Development in order to better participate in the global culture of computer science and technology that shapes the way we all live. The creative problem-solving and critical-thinking aspects of software development are my favorite parts this industry so far. My goal is to find a place on a team where I can continue to learn and grow in this new field.

Contact

720 - 207 - 7049



contact@bschweiz.co



www.bschweiz.co



linkedin.com/in/bschweiz



github.com/bschweiz

Projects

Happy Plants - Individual Project (See Code)

- Mobile-first web app for plant enthusiasts to add, update, manage individual plants and log/schedule upcoming waterings or check-ups
- Searchable technical plant database via Trefle.io API and live local weather via OpenWeather API
- Built with React and JSON Server

Nutshell - Group Project (See Code)

- Worked on a 4-person team to build a single-page Javascript app for sharing news, events, messages, and tasks with JSON database storage for userspecific data, accessing local and external APIs
- Responsible for developing and implementing message board features with live chat
- Built with modular design, agile workflow, and daily scum-style stand-ups

Education

Nashville Software School

Software Development Bootcap - Certificate

National Sun Yat-Sen University

Advanced Mandarin Chinese - Certificate

Amherst College

BA, Interdisciplinary Studies, Cum Laude

Software Experience

Nashville Software School

Software Developer -

Sep 2020 - Mar 2021

- Built single-page applications in ES6+ Javascript and React based on modular design principles
- Learned proper version-control workflow on group and individual projects on GitHub
- Developed effective remotely-located teamwork skills and communication techniques utilizing Slack and Zoom
- Server-side, test-driven development with Python, Django, and SQL

Professional Experience

Caravela Coffee

Feb 2016 - Feb 2018

Vertically integrated green coffee trading company with direct farmer purchasing in 9 countries and import operations globally

Country Director & Product Manager

Peru

- Responsible for all aspects of day-to-day operations within Peru, reporting directly to CFO & CEO daily as part of a globally dispersed team
- Hired and maintained a staff of 7 professionals working across 3 remote offices in Jaén, Lima, and Cusco
- Managed sourcing, milling, and export of 300+ metric tons of specialty grade green coffee to US, Australia, & Europe
- Negotiated business contracts with coffee cooperatives representing over 4,000 coffee farmers at ground-level

Supply Chain Management Apprentice

Colombia

- Self-taught Spanish with no priors to fluent in 3 months
- Learned various quality assurance protocol structures for domain-specific export standards and certifications
- Served as liaison and translator between visiting clients from US, Australia, Asia, and Europe and local producers

Thump Coffee Roasters

Oct 2013 - Feb 2016

Regional coffee wholesale/retailer with online portal and 5 cafés in Bend, OR and Denver, CO

Director of Coffee

Bend OR

- Structured annual coffee budgets and inventory management
- Responsible for roasting, packaging and shipping weekly production of over 1,000 lb. roasted coffee
- Managed online retail sales, order fulfillment, and web store maintenance

Retail Manager

Denver, CO

• Managed opening of 1500 sq. foot specialty coffee/bakery retail operation of over 15 employees

Fulbright Foundation, Taiwan

Jun 2010 - Jul 2011

Visiting Scholar/English Teaching Assistant

- Taught English at 4 public schools in Kaohsiung, Taiwan
- Achieved Mandarin Chinese speaking/writing/reading proficiency
- Elected to Cohort President by fellow Fulbrighters